Guide to the Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot Family Folger MS X.d.428 (1-203)
Folger Shakespeare Library
Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot family
1333-1705 (bulk 1548-1676)
Folger MS X.d.428 (1-203)
Folger Shakespeare Library
203.0 items (4 boxes)
Mostly consists of correspondence, as well as various financial documents, warrants, petitions, orders, physician instructions and other miscellaneous documents relating to the Cavendish, Talbot, Wentworth, and Slingsby families as well as to Sir Humphrey Style, and Stanley and Sarah Gower.
Cavendish family
Talbot family
Acquisition Information
The Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot family were acquired in May 1961 from the booksellers Lionel and Philip Robinson.
Provenance
The Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot family form part of the Phillipps' collection, nos. 20556-20558.
Many of the papers are included in Joseph Hunter's History of Hallamshire (see bibliography) and belonged to John Wilson of Broomhead Hall (1719-1783). Wilson had acquired these from a Mr. Stainforth of Darnell, a Mr. Bosville of Gunthwaite and Sir Thomas Wentworth of Bretton, and as two groups in this collection are letters to and/or from a John Stainforth and various members of the Wentworth families, it seems probable that they all formed part of the same collection. Wilson's collection was still intact in 1806; in 1843 it was dispersed and sold to Mr. Thorpe, a London bookseller, who sold many items to James Newman of High Holborn and he in his turn to Sir Thomas Phillipps. A.N.L. Munby describes their provenance as "Ex bibl. Miscellaneous."
Related Materials
Talbot Papers (MS 3192-3206) and Shrewsbury Papers (MS 694-710) at the Lambeth Palace Library, London.
Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury
Account book of Elizabeth, Countess of Shrewsbury, kept by her steward Edward Whalley, 1589 September 9-1592 July 12. Folger MS V.b.308.
Account book of Sir William and Lady Cavendish of Chatsworth, 1548 Michaelmas-1550. Folger MS X.d.486.
E. Williams watermark collection, see Folger MS L.f.358 (Her answer to the bill of complaint of her son, Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, January 30, 1605/6.)
Papers of the Bagot family, see Folger MS L.a.843, L.a.844.
George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury
Lease for lives from George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, to Lawrence Stile and his wife, 1575 January 11. Folger MS Z.c.40 (6).
Papers of the Bagot family, see Folger MS L.a.71, 72, 74, 441, 442, 714-722, 781-827, 932, 933, 1025, 1040.
Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury
Autograph letter signed from Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, Sheffield Castle, to Sir Humphrey Ferrers 1594 June 3. Folger MS X.c.129.
Autograph letter signed from Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, to George Abell, ca. 1600 March 15. Folger MS X.c.81.
Autograph letter signed from Gilbert and Mary Talbot, Goodrich Castle, Herefordshire, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1575/6 January 12. Folger MS X.c.76.
Leake, Thomas, d. 1598. Register of deer, hinds and stags, killed in Sherwood Forest, 1591-1598. Folger MS V.b.152.
Letters signed from Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, to Sir Richard Verney and Sir Humphrey Ferrers [manuscript], 1602-1605. Folger MS X.c.86 (1-4).
Letters signed from the Privy Council, 1596-1793 (bulk 1596-1634). Folger MS G.b.14 (2, 3, 5, 8). Four letters signed by him as privy councilor.
Loseley collection, 1489-1682 (bulk 1538-1630), see Folger MS L.b.634 Copy of a Privy Council ruling, July 13, 1613.
Papers of the Bagot family, see Folger MS L.a.828-842.
Copy of proclamation of Court of Claims to persons claiming the right to perform any service at the coronation of James I, King of England, July 13, 1603, 17th century. Folger MS X.d.88.
Other Formats
Also available on microfilm, Film Fo 3721 (reduction ratio 14:1, 33 feet).
Also available as digital images in LUNA http://titania.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/p8zh3f
Some letters are transcribed in Joseph Hunter's Hallamshire: The History and Topography.. ., p. 84, 107-124 (see bibliography): X.d.428 (2, 7-10, 12, 15, 17, 21, 25-27, 28 (last part only), 29, 36, 41, 44, 49, 51, 53, 59-60, 62-63, 69, 72, 75-77, 82-83, 85-87, 89, 91, 107-108, 110-115, 119, 121, 123-125, 129, 179).
Transcriptions of X.d.428 (64) and X.d.428 (73) appear on pages 318 and 322 of Hunter's Biographical Memoirs of Sir William Saint Loe... (see bibliography).
Scope and Content
The Papers of the Cavendish-Talbot family contain 175 autograph letters signed, as well as various financial documents, warrants, petitions, orders, physician instructions and other miscellaneous documents relating to the Cavendish, Talbot, Wentworth, and Slingsby families as well as to Sir Humphrey Style, and Stanley Gower.
Divided into six series: Cavendish and Talbot family papers, 1548-1607; Wentworth family papers, [1542?], 1624-1705; Slingsby family of Scryven papers, 1586-1634; Sir Humphrey Style letter, ca. 1629; Stanley Gower papers, 1636-1658; and miscellaneous documents, 1500-1548.
Most of the papers are autograph letters; several are written by an amanuensis and signed by the writer. Well-known place-names and personal names are modernized. Dates when not given are supplied, often tentatively, with a few given as undated. If a wax seal on a letter is whole and undamaged, this is noted. Additional manuscripts relating to the Countess of Shrewsbury appear in the Related Materials section of this finding aid.
Series 1: The Cavendish and Talbot family papers contain letters and miscellaneous documents. The majority of the letters are addressed to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, either as Lady Cavendish, Lady St. Loe, or as Countess of Shrewsbury, and are from her family and friends. Many mention Lady Arbella Stuart, the Countess of Shrewsbury's grand-daughter. Some are instructions to her steward and men of affairs and mention matters concerning the running of the estates and the building of Chatsworth. Others, particularly those from her stepson Gilbert Talbot, her daughter Mary, and her sons Charles and William, give her a survey of the news of the day, and events at court. The Wingfields answer at some length enquiries as to suitable New Year's gifts for the queen. Though Mary, Queen of Scots, was in the keeping of her husband, the Earl of Shrewsbury, during much of the time covered by the letters, there are few references to her, although two well-known letters in which the Earl tells of the possibility and then the certainty of Mary, Queen of Scots, being put in his charge are in this collection. A few refer to the differences which arose between the Earl and Countess. There are several household accounts, and an inventory of the goods of Francis Talbot, deceased. Twenty-three of the letters are written by women, including the Countesses of Kent, Lennox, Northumberland and Shrewsbury (both Elizabeth and her daughter Mary); Grace Cavendish; Lady Frances Cobham; Elizabeth (Leake) Leche; Lady Frances Pierrepont; Lady Margaret St. Loe; Lady Dorothy Stafford; Anne Talbot; and Elizabeth Wingfield.
Series 2: The Wentworth family papers contain letters and miscellaneous documents. There were many Wentworths in Yorkshire, including the Wentworths of Elmsall and Broadsworth, the Wentworths of West Bretton, the Wentworths of South Elmsall, and the Wentworths of Woolley. Most of these letters are to and from the Wentworths of West Bretton and Woolley. There are two from William Wentworth, later 2nd earl of Strafford, and some accounts on matters affecting his estates. Two orders are signed by Sir Thomas Wentworth, later Earl of Strafford; one by John Lambert. Some letters bear postal markings: X.d.428 (149, 156, 158, 168).
Series 3: The Slingsby family letters contain letters of the Slingsby family of Scriven, Yorkshire. Most are to Sir Henry Slingsby (d. 1634, father of Sir Henry 1602-1658) from other members of the family. A number arise out of his vice-presidency of the Council of the North and concern parliamentary affairs. Correspondents include Sir Henry Slingsby, his father Francis, his brother Sir William, his nephews Guilford and Sir Robert, his cousins William Byrnand and Sir Francis Trappes-Byrnand, his son-in-law Sir Thomas Metcalfe, his grandson Sir George Marwood, and his cousin Henry, Earl of Northumberland. Other correspondents are Sir Charles Cavendish, Peter Benson, Thomas, Lord Fairfax, Sir John Gibson, Christopher Mather, Robert Norton, Phanuell Otbie, Sir Robert Cecil, later Earl of Salisbury, Christopher Wade, Thomas Wardropp, Edward Wilson, Samuel Wortley, and William Wycliffe. A few of the letters are sent to/from Dublin.
Series 4: Sir Humphrey Style letter is to his wife Elizabeth.
Series 5: The Gower family letters are from Stanley Gower and his wife to their close friends John and Mary Stainforth of Darnall, Yorkshire, 1636-1658. Stanley Gower was rector of Brampton Bryan, Herefordshire, and his patron was first Sir Robert Harley and then Sir Edward Harley. Several letters refer to the disturbances of the civil wars, but not to the prolonged siege in 1643.
Series 6: The Miscellaneous documents consist of a copy of a lease, will, and receipt, apparently unrelated to any of the above families.
Arrangement
Originally bound in three volumes enclosed in a large red box resembling a volume. The papers had been numbered in pencil and were in sequence but as there was no discernible order in the arrangement and as many had become detached and were in need of repair, the volumes were broken up and the letters were divided into six series by family, with unrelated items placed in Series 6: Miscellaneous documents.
Within each series, the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by writer, with unidentified writers appearing at the end of the series, and then chronologically. Series 1: Cavendish-Talbot family papers and Series 2: Wentworth family papers are divided into two subseries: 1.1 Correspondence and 1.2 Other documents. The papers in the other documents subseries, as well as Series 6: Miscellaneous documents, are arranged chronologically.
Bibliography
A Calendar of the Shrewsbury and Talbot Papers in Lambeth Palace Library and the College of Arms. 2 vols. London, 1966, 1971.
Cooper, J.P., ed. Wentworth Papers 1597-1628. Camden 4th series, vol. 12. London: Royal Historical Society, 1973.
Durant, David N. Bess of Hardwick: Portrait of an Elizabethan Dynast. Rev. ed. London, 1999.
Eales, J. Puritans and Roundheads: The Harleys of Brampton Bryan. Cambridge, 1990. [mentions Stanley Gower]
Hunter, Joseph. Biographical Memoirs of Sir William Saint Loe, Captain of the Guard to Queen Elizabeth; with Original Letters. The Retrospective Review. 2nd ser., 2. 1828. 314-25.
Hunter, Joseph. Hallamshire: The History and Topography of the Parish of Sheffield in the County of York. London, 1869.
Letters of the Lady Brilliana Harley, Wife of Sir Robert Harley, of Brampton Bryan, Knight of the Bath. Camden Society Publications [1st ser.], 58. London, 1854. [mentions Stanley Gower]
Munby, A.N.L. The Formation of the Phillipps Library from 1841 to 1872. Phillipps Studies no. 4. Cambridge, 1956.
Munby, A.N.L. The Dispersal of the Phillipps Library. Phillipps Studies no. 5. Cambridge, 1960.
Smith, Geoffrey Ridsdill. Without Touch of Dishonour: The Life and Death of Sir Henry Slingsby 1602-1658. Kineton: Roundwood Press, 1968.
Availability
Collection is open for research. For information about applying for a Reader Card see: http://www.folger.edu/Content/Collection/Reader-Information/.
To request digital images, please fill out and submit a Photo Resources Order Form: http://www.folger.edu/photo_resources.cfm.
Gower, Sarah, d. 1661?; Gower, Stanley; Shrewsbury, Gilbert Talbot, Earl of, 1552-1616; Shrewsbury, Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of, 1527?-1608; Shrewsbury, George Talbot, Earl of, ca. 1522-1590; Slingsby, Henry, 1559 or 60-1634; Style, Humphrey, 1594 or 5-1659; Deeds -- Manuscripts; Family papers -- England; Financial records -- Manuscripts; Inventories -- Manuscripts; Legal documents -- Manuscripts; Letters -- Manuscripts; Manuscripts -- England; Memorandums -- Manuscripts; Petitions -- Manuscripts; Warrants -- Manuscripts; Wills -- Manuscripts
- Cavendish-Talbot family papers, 1548-1607; Series 1; X.d.428 (1-147)
  - Correspondence, 1.1
    - Letter from Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel, Arundel House, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, 1607 May 25; X.d.428 (1)
      Acknowledges his grandmother's favors.
      Seal intact.
      Digital image(s)
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/y803g8
    - Letter from Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel, Arundel House, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, 1607? June 27; X.d.428 (2)
      Arundel had originally wanted the countess to be his son's godmother, but now the queen has requested to be the godmother.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/nnei8f
    - Letter from Nicholas Booth to Mr. Thomas Kniveton, ca. 1580? April 4; X.d.428 (3)
      Refers to the differences between the Earl and Countess of Shrewsbury. The Earl has written to the Queen and some of the Privy Council "touching some harde and vnderect dealing, by my Lady and M[aste]r harry Cavendish." Make sure Lord Talbot goes to the Earl before he goes to the Countess. Business news.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/7yz4oy
    - Letter from Sir Charles Cavendish, Welbeck, Nottinghamshire?, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1585? November 6; X.d.428 (4)
      Unable to leave for Sheffield because of an attack of gout.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/vq12mz
    - Letter from Sir Charles Cavendish, Coldharbour (Cooldherber), London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1600? June 18; X.d.428 (5)
      He and his brother William have been at Mr. Dales and have spoken with the old gentlewoman, who has promised the Queen not to conclude any marriage "with out makinge hir priuy vnto it soe that for that espetiall cause she wisheth your la[dyship's] presence," who is "best able to attayne it sonest." William bought a jewel and presented it in their mother's name, but "the mayd would receaue non with out hir mothers consent."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/9dwl24
    - Letter from Sir Charles Cavendish, Leicester, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Dowager Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, ca. 1600; X.d.428 (6)
      Informs her of the arrival of her son-in-law and daughter, the Earl and Countess of Shrewsbury.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/o43a77
    - Letter from Grace Cavendish, Tutbury, Staffordshire, to Jane Kniveton, ca. 1585? October 10; X.d.428 (7)
      Asks her aunt to deliver a letter from her husband about his suit "to my honorable good lady," to whom she also sends two fat capons and a hundred wardens (baking pears).
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/3n833c
    - Letter from Grace Cavendish, Dowbridge, Derbyshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1589? June 27; X.d.428 (8)
      Refers to a letter received by the countess from Henry Cavendish, Grace's husband, on his way to Constantinople.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/8rc06a
    - Letter from Henry Cavendish, Tutbury, Staffordshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1570; X.d.428 (9)
      Informs her of the death of a servant in a duel. At the end of the letter is a note from Elizabeth to her husband, the Earl of Shrewsbury, with a request to "retarne thys."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/g04p8c
    - Letter from Henry Cavendish, Coldharbour (Coleherbert), London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1585? November 6; X.d.428 (10)
      Refutes rumors that his mother has heard that he is spending his time in London playing at dice.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/4w2t3u
    - Letter from Henry Cavendish, Tutbury, Staffordshire, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1605 December 31; X.d.428 (11)
      Accompanies a simple New Year's gift.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/6g8g81
    - Letter from Richard Cavendish, "Grymston haule in Suffolke" (i.e. Grimston End, Suffolk?), to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1570 July 12; X.d.428 (12)
      A request to take his niece, aged 18, into her service.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/u20kpd
    - Letter from Sir William Cavendish, Chatsworth, Derbyshire, to Lady Elizabeth Cavendish, ca. 1550 April 13; X.d.428 (13)
      Asks her to pay eight pounds for certain oats.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/gen5z0
    - Letter from Sir William Cavendish, Chatsworth, to Sir Humphrey Bradborne and Mr. Thomas Babington, ca. 1555 August 25; X.d.428 (14)
      Asks them to investigate the forcible entry of his house at Medowpleck (Derbyshire) by Henry Cryche and "dyvers mysdemeaned persons," who cast out the wife and children of Cavendish's shepherd, contrary to "certen statutes."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/p6g7ug
    - Letter from George Chaworth, written from court, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, 1606/7 February 13; X.d.428 (15)
      Requests that she ask his uncle, George Chaworth, to speak on his behalf to another uncle, Henry Chaworth, who is determined to settle his estate.
      Seal almost intact.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/3s3xql
    - Letter from Frances Brooke, Baroness Cobham, Cobham, Kent, to Lady Elizabeth St. Loe, 1564? October 21; X.d.428 (16)
      Has enclosed the breadth and length of a caul for the queen of the same work. Is expecting the birth of a child (see X.d.428 (61)).
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/4ce5up
    - Letter from William Brooke, Baron Cobham, the court at Richmond, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Dowager Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, 1595/6 February 27; X.d.428 (17)
      Understands from his cousin John Manners that a search may be made in certain grounds of hers for such black stone as he needs for his buildings.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/e0k446
    - Letter from James Crompe, Chatsworth, to Lady Elizabeth St. Loe, 1565 or 1566 November 20; X.d.428 (18)
      Gives his opinion on certain tutors for her sons. Mentions the paviour's progress at Chatsworth.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/z558aj
    - Letter from James Crompe, Chatsworth, to Lady Elizabeth St. Loe, 1560 or 1566 February 27; X.d.428 (19)
      Details about the building of Chatsworth.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/jb0msx
    - Letter from George Clifford, Earl of Cumberland, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1603 June or 1605 August; X.d.428 (20)
      Has been preparing for his majesty's coming to this "ruinated place." The bearer will speak to her concerning his daughter.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/q3v28w
    - Letter from William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, Clare Hall Clare College, Cambridge, to Marcella Linacre, Chatsworth, 1569? February 23; X.d.428 (21)
      Has just brought George (a relative of hers) from Ely to Cambridge, and requests payment for George's expenses.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/7i5g9f
    - Letter from William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1600 November 12; X.d.428 (22)
      The Star Chamber is unable to hear their matter touching concealments that day. Reports on a case in Chancery involving Mr. Barlow and Mr. Blunt, who liketh to be defended by the earl of Shrewsbury. The queen is coming to Whitehall; the Moscovy ambassador is expected.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/l2mdrg
    - Letter from William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Hardwick, 1604 July 4; X.d.428 (23)
      It is thought Parliament will end this Saturday. Four days ago lady Arbella spoke to the king on his behalf. The Earl of Pembroke's marriage is deferred by three months.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/027w99
    - Letter from William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, ca. 1600; X.d.428 (24)
      The judges have made stay for Basford's matter. This morning he was with the Master of the Pells. Lady Arbella is at Edmonton and is very well.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/dubzr4
    - Letter from William Cavendish, Earl of Devonshire, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1605 April 23; X.d.428 (25)
      Names the godparents of Princess Mary, one of them being Lady Ar[a]bella [Stuart]. Has heard that the Earl of Shrewsbury was not able to travel. The Queen of Spain had a son, and the Spanish ambassador held a celebration with fireworks. The new Pope will favor the French more than the Spanish.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/z2et1l
    - Letter from Robert Devereux, Earl of Essex, written from court, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1590/1 March 23; X.d.428 (26)
      Recommends the bearer, Christopher Hannam, to her service. Lady of Kent and Sir John Wingfield also recommend him.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/cb1e5o
    - Letter from Walter Devereux, Earl of Essex, Carrickfergus (Knockfergus), County Antrim, Ireland, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1573 October 23; X.d.428 (27)
      Recommends the bearer, a Mr. Candishe, a soldier, to his attention. Comments on the difficulty of training gentlemen of our nation to endure pains. Addresses the Earl of Shrewsbury as his "kinsman."
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/7p59e3
    - Letter from Hugh Fitzwilliam, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Chatsworth, 1570 July 28; X.d.428 (28)
      Survey of European and court news. Mentions Mary, Queen of Scots, the Earl of Sussex, the Earl of Lennox, and the Duke of Norfolk, in the aftermath of the Northern Rebellion.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/422tcx
    - Letter from Hugh Fitzwilliam, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, Chatsworth, 1571 September 21; X.d.428 (29)
      European and court news. The duke [of Norfolk] was committed to the Tower, most likely because he sent money to assist the Scottish lords, who sided with Mary, Queen of Scots. The Queen is to go to Lord Burleigh's on Sunday, where the Earl of Oxford is to marry Burleigh's daughter. In news from France, there is "nothing spoken of the Quenes Maiesties marriage." The murderer of the Earl of Lennox has been executed.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/2m85q5
    - Letter from Hugh Fitzwilliam, London, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1573/4 February 3; X.d.428 (30)
      Suggests that the best place the two parties could meet in greatest secrecy would be at his cousin Anthony Wingfield's, where his unsuspecting cousin could have a sight of her [one of the daughters of the Countess of Shrewsbury?]. European and Irish news (mentions Count Montgomery, the Prince of Orange, the queen mother and her son the King of Poland).
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/an2u3m
    - Letter from Edward Foxe, Chatsworth, to Lady Elizabeth St. Loe, ca. 1565 December 8; X.d.428 (31)
      Justifies his conduct as her gamekeeper.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/q90kxd
    - Letter from Alexander Gordon, Bishop-elect of Galloway, Sheffield, to Elizabeth Hardwick Talbot, Countess of Shrewsbury, 1571 May 3; X.d.428 (32)
      The Queen has agreed to remove the chaplain to the Queen of Scots and let his elder son remain. The Queen of Scots suffers the religion patiently and he hopes to profit her further.
      http://luna.folger.edu/luna/servlet/s/di57z9
    - Letter from Richard Grey, Tutbury, to George Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury, 1584? November 28; X.d.428 (33)